In the year 845, the Colossal Titan
and the Armored Titan suddenly appeared
and destroyed one of humanity's
walls-- and everyday life with it.
Humanity abandoned Wall Maria,
lost 20% of its population
and one-third of its territory,
and was forced to
retreat behind Wall Rose.
And then, in the year 850...
Humanity's fight back...
...is just beginning!
The target is the
Colossal Titan dead ahead!
This is our chance!
Don't let it get away!
Hey, there.
It's been five years since we met.
Unknown are the names
of the flowers that have been trampled
Birds have fallen to the earth
and long for the wind
Prayers won't solve anything
Only the will to fight
can change the here and now!
O pigs who laugh at the resolve
to walk over corpses to move forward
Livestock complacency? False prosperity?
Give us the freedom of dying,
starving wolves!
The humiliation of being caged
is what triggers us to fight back
We hunters slaughter prey
beyond the castle walls,
consumed with surging bloodlust,
as our crimson bows and arrows
pierce scarlet holes into the twilight
"First Battle"
"The Struggle for Trost, Part 1"
He went for the cannons!
And he didn't take out
the gate by accident, either!
He does have intelligence...!
Still, this is the perfect chance!
He's the only one
who can destroy the wall!
If I can just take him out...!
Too slow!
Got you!
Wha...?!
Hot!
Go!
I missed?!
No...
The Colossal Titan disappeared!
Eren! Did you beat it?!
No!
It's just like five years ago!
He suddenly appeared,
then suddenly disappeared!
I'm sorry. I let him get away.
What are you apologizing for?
We were scared stiff--
Hey! This is no time for that!
The wall's been broken!
We have to hurry and seal
it before the Titans get in again!
What are you doing?!
The Colossal Titan Response
Operation is already underway!
Return to HQ at once!
Anyone who's come into contact
with it, remember to give a report!
Yes, Sir!
We pray for the
advance team's success!
Take only the
absolute bare necessities!
Please evacuate
in a calm manner!
If they break through here,
we'll have another tragedy just
like five years ago on our hands!
We must hold the Titans off here!
Prepare to intercept!
Fire!
Charge!
You cadets have successfully graduated!
You are now proper soldiers!
I have high hopes
for you in this operation!
Don't worry, Hanna.
I promise I'll keep you safe.
Franz...
Are you okay, Armin?!
I-I'm fine!
I'll calm down soon enough!
Still, this is bad!
We don't have the technology to
quickly seal an 8-meter-high hole!
And we never did manage to unearth
that big rock near the front gate!
Unless we seal the hole,
this city's as good as lost!
It's only a matter of time
until Wall Rose is breached!
In fact, if they ever feel like it,
they can pretty much wipe
out humanity anytime they want!
Armin!
Calm down! This isn't like last time!
Humanity won't give in
to the Titans anymore!
I'm sorry...
I'm all right...
Come, now.
Are you playing seriously?
There. I win again.
We square off once a month, yet you
never seem to improve at all, Pyxis.
Oh, no, I am just no
match for you, Lord Wald.
You're the top officer in charge
of the entire southern territory.
How do you hope
to triumph over the Titans
with such paltry skill and intellect?
Commander Pyxis!
I bring a message!
How uncouth! Who are you--?!
The Colossal Titan has appeared in Trost!
The gate has been destroyed!
Mm. This is a fine drink, indeed.
As a fellow warrior on the field
of battle, I will humbly accept it.
H-Hey! Wait, Pyxis!
Pyxis! Hey! Wait just a minute!
I forbid you to leave!
Assemble your troops
immediately and defend my domain!
That is your duty!
Lord Wald.
As we speak, soldiers in Trost
are literally risking their lives in battle.
Commander.
I will ready the horses.
I presume many lives are
being lost as well.
Right now, at this very moment.
Hmph. Insignificant lives, I'm sure.
Forget about them.
Your presence there
won't change anything anyway;
you continually lose
to me in our tabletop skirmishes!
Fear not, Your Lordship.
Should he face the
Titans on a real battlefield,
the commander will not
need to be as lenient with them.
Enough.
Lord Wald.
Please have another pleasant and
peaceful day as always.
H-Hey!
Pyxis!
Come back! Pyxis!
As practiced,
you will now split into your squads
and perform resupply, message
relay, and Titan-clearing duties
under the command
of the Garrison Regiment!
The Garrison Regiment's
intercept squad will take the vanguard!
"Vanguard"
The Cadets, led by
"Middle Guard"
the support squad, will take the middle guard!
"Rearguard"
And the Garrison Regiment's elite squads
will take the rearguard!
Additionally, I've received word
that the advance team
has been wiped out!
The outer gate has been breached,
and the Titans have been allowed inside!
In other words, the Armored Titan
could very well appear again
and demolish the inner gate at any time!
--You can't be serious...
--You gotta be kidding me...
If they end up breaching Rose too...!
Quiet!
The vanguard is currently
engaged with the enemy!
This defense operation
has but one objective:
to defend Wall Rose until the
citizens have finished evacuating!
Also, as I'm sure you're well aware,
desertion is punishable by death!
Be prepared to lay down your lives!
Dismissed!
Sir!
Why today?
I would've been on my
way to the interior tomorrow...
Are you okay?!
No, no, no, no...
Move!
Hey, Jean! What's wrong?!
"What's wrong?!"
That's easy for you to say,
you suicidal maniac!
You want to join the Scouts!
You're ready to
be Titan chow anytime!
--But I was headed for the interior tomorrow!
--Calm down!
You expect me to calm
down and accept death?!
No!
Think back!
Think back to the three years
of sweat and blood we endured!
So many times we came close
to dying during those three years!
Some people did die.
Some ran off. Others were kicked out.
But we survived!
Right?!
I'm sure we can survive today, too!
You can just survive today
and leave for the interior tomorrow!
Damn!
Let's go, Daz! Quit your damn cryin'!
R-Right...
Eren.
If the battle gets chaotic,
come find me.
Huh? We're in different squads!
If the situation falls apart,
things won't go according to plan.
I'll protect you!
What the hell are you--
Cadet Ackermann.
You're in the rearguard. Special orders.
Come with me.
I-I'm not skilled enough!
I'll only be a burden!
I am not asking for your opinion.
The citizens' evacuation
is behind schedule.
We need as many elite
soldiers near them as possible.
--B-But...!
--Hey!
Cut the crap, Mikasa!
Quit freaking out like everyone else!
Humanity's on the
verge of extinction here!
This is no time to go and
impose your own selfish rules!
I'm sorry. I wasn't thinking clearly.
I do have one thing to ask.
Please don't die.
I ain't gonna die.
I can't die yet!
Because I still don't know
what this world is really like!
Surviving historical documents
say nothing about the origin of the Titans.
Most everything remains unknown.
The things we do know about now,
including Titan ecology,
are based entirely on the latest
reports from the Scout Regiment.
We've been unable to determine if
the Titans possess human-like intelligence.
As such, there've been no cases
to date of mutual communication.
Titan physiology is fundamentally
different from that of other living beings.
They lack reproductive organs,
and it is unclear how they reproduce,
but they primarily possess male-like physiques.
They have extremely
high body temperatures,
and, perplexingly enough, they show
no interest in anything but humans.
Consuming people is the
Titans' sole principle of behavior,
but given that they've existed for over
a century in a human-less environment,
we can surmise that the very act
of feeding is unnecessary for them.
In other words, it's believed that
they are not motivated by predation,
but by bloodlust.
And, most of all, the Titans'
tremendous vitality is the primary reason
that humankind has been
so greatly overwhelmed.
Humanity has long
possessed cannon technology,
but that alone wasn't
enough to combat them.
Even when their heads are
blown off, the Titans don't die.
Additionally, although
there is some variability,
their heads will fully regenerate
in only a minute or two.
You can't be serious...
Their size is bad enough as it is...
Sir! Does that mean
the Titans are immortal?!
They are not immortal.
There is one way to defeat a Titan.
You target here.
When severely damaged here,
a Titan will die without regenerating.
That's where these two
flesh-paring blades come in.
A successful strike to a
Titan's weak spot with these
will cause its immediate death,
with no time to regenerate whatsoever.
Hey, Armin.
This is the perfect chance, don't you think?
If we take care of business in this first
battle before we've even joined the Scouts,
we rookies will shoot up
the ranks for sure!
Yeah. No question about it.
Just so you know,
you aren't the only ones in our class
who wanna join the Scouts.
You beat us to the punch earlier,
but you won't outdo us this time!
Sounds like a challenge, Thomas!
Whoever takes out the most Titans wins!
--Don't go messin' with the scores!
--Squad 34, move out!
Bolster the vanguard!
All right! Let's go!
That many Titans?!
The vanguard's been totally routed!
What are they doing?!
Those hot shots usually act all tough!
I figured things would
be bad, but not like this!
An Abnormal!
Stop!
Huh...?
What the hell are you doing?!
--Eren!
--Don't go off on your own!
Get back here, damn it!
You're gonna pay for killing Thomas!
I won't let you get away! I won't!
Eren!
Stop! Please don't!
Why...?
Why am I watching
as my friends get eaten?
Why... can't I move...?
A-Armin...
Eren! Eren!
Eren!
What is it, Armin?
My grandpa secretly had this!
It's a book about the outside world!
A book about the outside world?!
Isn't it illegal to have those?
You're gonna get arrested!
This is no time to be saying that!
According to this book,
most of the world is covered
in water called a "sea"!
And this "sea" is entirely saltwater!
Salt?!
Y-You're lying!
Salt is a treasure trove!
I'm sure merchants
would've snatched it all up!
You can't, though! The sea is that big!
Yeah, right--
There's a lot more than loads of salt, too!
Fiery water! Lands of ice!
Sandy snowfields!
The outside world
must be many times larger
than the inside of these walls!
The outside world...
And, this is still a secret,
but my mom and dad are planning
to venture into the outside world!
The outside world, huh...
Hey, Eren.
I hope we can explore
the outside world too someday!
Eren!
I refuse to die here...
Listen, Armin...
You told me about it...
So I have... to see it...
The outside world...!
Eren!
Hurry!
Your dreams are where your heart is
They're more fragile than life itself
Over and over you cast them aside,
only to find more
Now, rest in peace
Pounding impulses defile the things we wish for
and the more we forget
the more we remember again
In this beautiful, cruel world
all I can do is ask why we're still alive
Oh, with our strength--and our weakness--
what are we going to protect if there's no sense
to anything anymore?
Suddenly, it begins to rain.
The quiet sound of the rainfall...
The damp air...
The faintly sweet smell of rain...
They remind Mikasa of
a ghastly incident in her past.
"The World the Girl Saw"
"The Struggle for Trost, Part 2"